Finding aid for John Duke papers CA.MS.00066
Smith College Archives
- Series I. SCORES, 1921-1984; undated
  - File Copies
    - Miscellaneous
      - "Twang the Lyre for Sophia," for the Smith College Faculty Show, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 583)
  - Scripts and Texts
    - Scripts
      - Between Whistles, A Factory Follies, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 584)
      - "The Cat That Walked by Himself," early version, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 585-86)
      - "The Cat That Walked by Himself," final version, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 587)
      - "For Whom the Bells Trill", undated (Box 22, Folder 588)
      - "Liberty, Totality, Sorority or Lady Macbeth of Northamsk," Smith College Faculty Show, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 589)
      - "Love among the Ruins," Smith College Faculty Show, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 590)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar", 1962 (Box 22, Folder 591-92)
    - Texts, miscellaneous, undated (Box 22, Folder 593)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Engraved plates for song no. 2, "Lullaby", 1923 (Box 22, Folder 594-95)
- Series II. BIOGRAPHICAL AND PERSONAL MATERIAL, 1922-1984; undated
  This series contains biographical sketches, newspaper clippings, tributes, photographs, and press releases pertaining to John Duke's life. Included are such personal items as programs of concerts Duke attended, a compilation of quotations in two notebooks, plus news clippings and miscellaneous papers about Duke's family, friends, colleagues, and finances.
  - General; biographical material, 1946; 1959 (Box 23, Folder 596)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 23, Folder 597)
  - Family: news clippings, programs, writings, 1939-83; undated (Box 23, Folder 598)
  - Financial, 1922-64; undated (Box 23, Folder 599)
  - Friends and colleagues: brochures, news clippings, photographs, 1946-79; undated (Box 24, Folder 600)
  - News clippings
    - Biographical, 1928-84 (Box 24, Folder 601)
    - Compositions, 1963; 1979-80 (Box 24, Folder 602)
    - Professional activities, 1920-84; undated (Box 24, Folder 603-605)
    - Recordings, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 606)
    - Press releases, general, 1922-84; undated (Box 24, Folder 607-608)
    - Publicity material for "The Yankee Pedlar", 1964; undated (Box 24, Folder 609)
  - Photographs
    - John Duke, 1926-67; undated (Box 24, Folder 610)
    - Family, undated (Box 24, Folder 611)
    - John Duke with groups, 1934-79; undated (Box 24, Folder 612)
    - Opera productions, 1959; 1962 (Box 24, Folder 613)
  - Tributes to John and Dorothy Duke, 1966-81; undated (Box 24, Folder 614)
  - Programs of concerts attended, 1945-84; undated (Box 24, Folder 615-617)
  - Notebooks of quotations, undated (Box 24, Folder 618-619)
- Series III. CORRESPONDENCE, 1913-1984
  This series has two sections: General and Publications. General correspondence consists mainly of personal and professional correspondence from family, friends, colleagues, college administrators, students, teachers, organizations, singers, and other musicians. The letters are arranged according to the name of the correspondent or organization. There are also six folders of drafts of outgoing correspondence (1977-84), arranged chronologically. Correspondence about Publication consists mainly of letters from music publishing companies and societies, publication contracts, copyright certificates, performance records, and royalty statements arranged by the name of the company or society. Also included is one folder of correspondence about text copyrights from publishers of some of the texts Duke set to music.
  - General
    - A - A1, 1920-83; undated (Box 25, Folder 620)
    - Aeolian Company, 1926-28; undated (Box 25, Folder 621)
    - Am - Az, 1921-81; undated (Box 25, Folder 622)
    - Auld, Louis, 1973-84; undated (Box 25, Folder 623)
    - Ba, 1928-83; undated (Box 25, Folder 624)
    - Baumann, Mordecai, 1948-52; undated (Box 25, Folder 625)
    - Be - Bl, 1920-84; undated (Box 25, Folder 626)
    - Belisle, John, 1968-77 (Box 25, Folder 627)
    - Berkley, Harold, 1943-44; undated (Box 25, Folder 628)
    - Berthold, Robert, 1973-75 (Box 25, Folder 629)
    - Bixler, J. Seelye, 1932-72 (Box 25, Folder 630)
    - Bo, 1932-84; undated (Box 25, Folder 631)
    - Bond, Katherine, 1980; undated (Box 25, Folder 632)
    - Boothman, Donald, 1971-83 (Box 25, Folder 633-634)
    - Br, 1920-81; undated (Box 25, Folder 635)
    - Brown, Oren, 1976-84 (Box 25, Folder 636)
    - Bu - Bz, 1920-80; undated (Box 25, Folder 637)
    - Burk, Elaine, 1978-80 (Box 25, Folder 638)
    - Ca - Cl, 1925-80; undated (Box 25, Folder 639)
    - Cannon, Franklin, 1920-29; undated (Box 25, Folder 640-642)
    - Charnley, Milne, undated (Box 25, Folder 643)
    - Co, 1929-83; undated (Box 25, Folder 644)
    - Compton, Earl and Jacqueline, 1969-74; undated (Box 25, Folder 645)
    - Conway, Jill and John, 1977-84 (Box 25, Folder 646)
      See also: Smith College
    - Copland, Aaron, 1928; 1955 (Box 25, Folder 647)
    - Cotton, Ann (niece), 1975-82 (Box 25, Folder 648)
    - Cr - Cu, 1947-81; undated (Box 25, Folder 649)
    - Da - Di, 1928-84 (Box 25, Folder 650)
    - Delaware Vocal Arts Festival, l961-84 (Box 25, Folder 651)
    - Dimmock, Ellalou, 1962-79; undated (Box 25, Folder 652)
    - Do - Dz, 1928-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 653)
    - Duke, Edward and Yvette (brother and sister-in-law), 1925-76 (Box 26, Folder 654)
    - Duke, Henry K. (brother), 1946-79; undated (Box 26, Folder 655)
    - Duke, Margaret (sister), 1926-42; undated (Box 26, Folder 656)
    - Duke, William T. and Margaret (brother and sister-in-law), 1942-79; undated (Box 26, Folder 657)
    - Duke family, miscellaneous, 1925-67; undated (Box 26, Folder 658)
    - Duyer, Debbie Royal, 1981-82 (Box 26, Folder 659)
    - E, 1928-79; undated (Box 26, Folder 660)
    - Edmonds, John, 1947-60 (Box 26, Folder 661)
    - Eisenberg, Maurice, 1943-48; undated (Box 26, Folder 662)
    - Evans, Margarita, 1982; undated (Box 26, Folder 663)
      See also: Publication, Society of Friends of John Duke
    - Ewing, Lora, 1976-82; undated (Box 26, Folder 664)
    - F, 1924-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 665)
    - Fairbank, Janet, undated (Box 26, Folder 666)
    - Falk, Robert B., 1951; 1955 (Box 26, Folder 667)
    - Finardi, Eloise Degenring, 1949-62; undated (Box 26, Folder 668)
    - Flint Civic Opera, 1960-61 (Box 26, Folder 669)
    - Fortson, Mary Lillian, 1968-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 670)
    - Frey, Frederick C., 1974-79 (Box 26, Folder 671)
    - Friedberg, Ruth, 1960-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 672-673)
    - G, 1920-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 674)
    - Gauthier, Eva, 1951-55; undated (Box 26, Folder 675)
    - Gephart, William, 1959; 1977 (Box 26, Folder 676)
    - Gramm, Donald, 1976-82; undated (Box 26, Folder 677)
    - Ha, 1926-82; undated (Box 26, Folder 678)
    - Hanks, John, undated (Box 26, Folder 679)
    - Harrell, Mack, 1945-52 (Box 26, Folder 680)
    - Harriman, Jenny, 1974-75 (Box 26, Folder 681)
    - Hartford School of Music, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 682)
    - Hartt Musical Foundation, 1953-61 (Box 26, Folder 683)
    - He - Hol, 1920-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 684)
    - Heatner, Carolyn, 1982-84 (Box 26, Folder 685)
    - Heritage (magazine), 1932; undated (Box 26, Folder 686)
    - Hillyer, Robert, 1948-53 (Box 26, Folder 687)
    - Holden, David and Margaret, 1979-83 (Box 26, Folder 688)
    - Hom - Hz, 1926-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 689)
    - Hunt, William, 1920-21 (Box 26, Folder 690)
    - I - J, 1920-84; undated (Box 26, Folder 691)
    - Jackson, Jessica, undated (Box 26, Folder 692)
    - Jenkins, Ben, 1981; undated (Box 26, Folder 693)
    - Johnston, Donald W., 1949-59; undated (Box 26, Folder 694)
    - K, 1925-84; undated (Box 27, Folder 695)
    - Kemper, Ruth, 1920-21; 1959 (Box 27, Folder 696)
    - Kennedy, Steven, 1948-58 (Box 27, Folder 697)
    - King, Benjamin Gibner, 1948-62; undated (Box 27, Folder 698)
    - Kraft, Marie Simmelink, 1947-50 (Box 27, Folder 699)
    - La - Le, 1925-84; undated (Box 27, Folder 700)
    - Langstaff, John Meredith, 1953-61 (Box 27, Folder 701)
    - Latella, Lynne, 1980-84 (Box 27, Folder 702)
    - Leedy, (Charles) Denoe, 1921-64; undated (Box 27, Folder 703-704)
    - Leslie, Grace, 1950-78 (Box 27, Folder 705)
    - Li - Lz, 1924-84; undated (Box 27, Folder 706)
    - Lister-Sink, Barbara, 1969-84; undated (Box 27, Folder 701-710)
    - Lubin, Ernest, 1948-76 (Box 27, Folder 711)
    - Mac/Mc, 1920-84; undated (Box 27, Folder 712)
    - McCalmont, David, Margaret, and Virginia, 1924-25; 1979 (Box 27, Folder 713)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1939-54; undated (Box 27, Folder 714)
    - McManus, Don, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 715)
    - Ma, 1921-81; undated (Box 27, Folder 716)
    - Marshall, Madeline (Mrs. Robert A. Simon), 1964-78; undated (Box 27, Folder 717)
    - Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1920-50; undated (Box 27, Folder 718)
    - Mason and Hamlin Company, 1920-31 (Box 27, Folder 719)
    - Me - Mz, 1920-80; undated (Box 27, Folder 720)
    - Milliette, Marie, 1977; undated (Box 27, Folder 721)
    - Milnes, Sherrill, 1979-83; undated (Box 27, Folder 722)
    - Mitchell, Hobart, 1949-61; undated (Box 27, Folder 723)
    - The Music Fund, 1928-29 (Box 27, Folder 724)
    - Na - Ne, 1925-83 (Box 27, Folder 725)
    - National Association for American Composers and Conductors, 1944-51 (Box 27, Folder 726)
    - National Association of Teachers of Singing, 1950-83; undated (Box 27, Folder 727-728)
    - National Music League, 1925-26 (Box 27, Folder 729)
    - Ni - No, 1925-83 (Box 28, Folder 730)
    - Nicholas, Louis, 1950-83 (Box 28, Folder 731-734)
    - Nickson, Richard, 1982-84; undated (Box 28, Folder 735-736)
    - O, 1928-84 (Box 28, Folder 737)
    - Pa - Ph, 1924-83; undated (Box 28, Folder 738)
    - Pacific Lyric Theatre, 1973-80 (Box 28, Folder 739)
    - Pazmor, Radiana, 1956-70 (Box 28, Folder 740)
    - Peabody Conservatory of Music, 1928-69 (Box 28, Folder 741)
    - Pepper, Max, 1951-79 (Box 28, Folder 742)
    - Phillips, Thomas and Ann, 1959-72; undated (Box 28, Folder 743)
    - Pi - Q, 1928-84; undated (Box 28, Folder 744)
    - Price, Nathan, 1948-51; undated (Box 28, Folder 745)
      See also: National Association of Teachers of Singing
    - Ra - Rh, 1920-82; undated (Box 28, Folder 746)
    - Randolph, Harold, 1921-26; undated (Box 28, Folder 747)
    - Raskin, Judith, 1964-72; undated (Box 28, Folder 748)
    - Ranung, Karen, 1979-84; undated (Box 28, Folder 749-750)
    - Rees, Gustave, 1924-76 (Box 28, Folder 751)
      See also: Publications, Carl Fischer, Inc. Publications, G. Schirmer, Inc.
    - Reneau, Jerald, 1973; undated (Box 28, Folder 752)
    - Ri - Ry, 1927-83; undated (Box 28, Folder 753)
    - Rivers, Richard and Roberta, 1955-79; undated (Box 28, Folder 754)
    - Ross, Gilbert and Gertrude, 1942-83; undated (Box 28, Folder 755)
    - Sa - Se, 1930-83; undated (Box 28, Folder 756)
    - Seagle, John, 1950-84; undated (Box 28, Folder 757-758)
    - Sessions, Roger, 1931-44; undated (Box 28, Folder 759)
    - Sh - Sk, 1930-81; undated (Box 29, Folder 760)
    - Shaw, Leora, 1964-79; undated (Box 29, Folder 761)
    - Shaw, Virginia, 1949-55; undated (Box 29, Folder 762)
    - Siver, Ruth, 1921-26; undated (Box 29, Folder 763)
    - S1 - Sp, 1920-79; undated (Box 29, Folder 764)
    - Smith, Gerald, 1951-74 (Box 29, Folder 765)
    - Smith College, 1923-82 (Box 29, Folder 766-767)
    - Smith College Clubs, 1928-32; 1968 (Box 29, Folder 768)
    - Snively, Susan, 1971; 1984 (Box 29, Folder 769)
    - Spofford, Grace, 1925; 1953-57 (Box 29, Folder 770)
    - St - Sz, 1913-74; undated (Box 29, Folder 771)
    - Sturges, Karen Duke (daughter), 1944-78; undated (Box 29, Folder 772)
    - Sturges, Morgan (granddaughter), 1981-84; undated (Box 29, Folder 773)
    - Swarthout, Gladys, 1948-49 (Box 29, Folder 774)
    - T - Th, 1928-84; undated (Box 29, Folder 775)
    - Tangeman, Nell, 1948-61; undated (Box 29, Folder 776)
    - Tassie, Phalen, 1952-57; undated (Box 29, Folder 777)
    - Thibault, Conrad, 1965; 1970 (Box 29, Folder 778)
    - Ti - Tz, 1925-79; undated (Box 29, Folder 779)
    - Trinity University, 1953-56; undated (Box 29, Folder 780)
    - U - V, 1951-84; undated (Box 29, Folder 781)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1964-72 (Box 29, Folder 782)
    - Varick, Richard, 1924-28 (Box 29, Folder 783)
    - WBUR - WNYC, 1946-64 (Box 29, Folder 784)
    - Wa, 1920-83; undated (Box 29, Folder 785)
    - We, 1923-82; undated (Box 29, Folder 786)
    - Webb, Mary Ellen, 1968-82; undated (Box 29, Folder 787)
    - Welch, Roy Dickinson, 1930-43 (Box 29, Folder 788)
    - Wells, Katherine Gladney, 1959-75 (Box 29, Folder 789)
    - Wh - Wi, 1924-80; undated (Box 29, Folder 790)
    - Wo - Wz, 1925-81; undated (Box 29, Folder 791)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1939-40 (Box 29, Folder 792)
    - Y, 1921-84 (Box 29, Folder 793)
    - Z, 1952-84; undated (Box 29, Folder 794)
    - Unidentified, 1929-83; undated (Box 29, Folder 795-797)
    - Drafts of outgoing letters, 1977-84; undated (Box 30, Folder 798-803)
  - Publication
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP): Correspondence, 1947-84 (Box 31, Folder 804-806)
    - ASCAP: performance records, 1947-83 (Box 31, Folder 807-809)
    - ASCAP: royalty statements, 1972-84 (Box 31, Folder 810)
    - Boosey and Hawkes, 1947-84 (Box 31, Folder 811-814)
      See also: box 34
    - Boston Music Company, 1969-77 (Box 31, Folder 815)
    - Elkan-Vogel Company, Inc.: correspondence, 1942-65 (Box 31, Folder 816)
    - Elkan-Yogel Company, Inc.: royalty statements, 1948-69 (Box 31, Folder 817)
      See also: Theodore J. Presser Company, box 34
    - Carl Fischer, Inc., 1922-84 (Box 31, Folder 818-824)
    - Mercury Music Corporation: correspondence and royalty statements, 1950-60 (Box 31, Folder 825)
    - Music Press, Inc., 1946-49 (Box 31, Folder 826)
    - Theodore J. Presser Company/Elkan-Vogel Co., Inc.: correspondence and royalty statements, 1973-84 (Box 31, Folder 827)
    - Recital Publications: correspondence, 1978-81; undated (Box 32, Folder 828)
    - R. D. Row Music Company: correspondence, 1949-64 (Box 32, Folder 829-830)
    - G. Schirmer, Inc.: correspondence, 1922-77 (Box 32, Folder 831-834)
    - G. Schirmer, Inc.: royalty statements, 1928-31 (Box 32, Folder 835-839)
      See also: box 34, 1946-84
    - Society of the Friends of John Duke: general, undated (Box 32, Folder 840)
    - Society of the Friends of John Duke: correspondence, 1982-84 (Box 32, Folder 841-845)
      See also: General, Margarita Evans
    - Southern Music Publishing Company, Inc.: correspondence, 1954-69 (Box 32, Folder 846-848)
    - Peer-Southern Organization: correspondence, 1971-83 See also: box 34 (Box 32, Folder 849-850)
      See also: box 3
    - Valley Music Press: royalty statements, 1944-84 (Box 32, Folder 851)
    - Miscellaneous music publishers: correspondence, 1921-81 (Box 32, Folder 852)
    - Miscellaneous publishers of poems: correspondence re text copyright, 1945-81 (Box 32, Folder 853)
  - Oversize
    - Copyright certificates, 1944-77 (Box 33, Folder 854)
    - Boosey and Hawkes, Inc.: contracts, 1948-80 (Box 33, Folder 855)
    - Boosey and Hawkes, Inc.: royalty statements, 1949-75 (Box 33, Folder 856)
    - Boston Music Company: contracts, 1969; 1971 (Box 33, Folder 857)
    - Boston Music Company: royalty statements, 1970-82 (Box 33, Folder 858)
    - Elkan-Yogel Company, Inc.: contracts, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 859)
    - Mercury Music Corporation: contract, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 860)
    - Music Press, Inc.: contracts, 1947; 1949 (Box 33, Folder 861)
    - R. D. Row Music Company: contracts, 1949-53 (Box 33, Folder 862)
    - R. D. Row Music Company: royalty statements, 1951 -77 (Box 33, Folder 863)
    - G. Schirmer, Inc.: contracts, 1922-70 (Box 33, Folder 864)
    - Carl Fischer, Inc.: contracts, 1947-74 (Box 33, Folder 865)
    - Carl Fischer, Inc.: royalty statements, 1949-83 (Box 33, Folder 866-867)
    - Southern Music Company, Peer-Southern Org.: contracts, 1955-79 (Box 33, Folder 868)
    - Southern Music Company: royalty statements, 1962-84 (Box 33, Folder 869-871)
- Series IV. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1916-1984
  This series consists primarily of scrapbooks and concert programs which document Duke's career as a composer, teacher, and pianist. The scrapbooks contain reviews, publicity material, and programs for performances either by John duke or of John Duke's compositions. They are arranged chronologically, with the oversized scrapbooks in a separate sequence. The programs are primarily for performances by Duke or of Duke's compositions. They are arranged chronologically. Also included are programs of performances by piano students of John Duke. There is a small amount of printed material and correspondence related to some of John Duke's professional affiliations.
  - Scrapbooks
    - Programs, reviews, news clippings, 1916-22 (Box 34, Folder 872)
      See also: scrapbooks - oversize
    - Programs, 1923-26 (Box 34, Folder 873)
    - Reviews of piano performances by John Duke, 1921-36 (Box 34, Folder 874)
    - Reviews and news clippings for "The Yankee Pedlar" and lecture-recitals on "6 Poems By Emily Bronte", 1962-75 (Box 34, Folder 875)
    - Reviews and news clippings for "Captain Lovelock" and "The Sire de Maletroit", 1953-60 (Box 34, Folder 876)
  - Scrapbooks - oversize
    - Reviews and news clippings, 1916-75 (Box 35, Folder 877)
    - Programs, 1935-43 (Box 35, Folder 878)
    - News clippings, 1939-77 (Box 35, Folder 879)
    - Programs and news clippings, 1953-54 (Box 35, Folder 880)
    - Programs and news clippings, 1956; 1962-67 (Box 36, Folder 881-882)
    - Programs, 1967-74 (Box 36, Folder 883)
    - Programs, 1975-80 (Box 37, Folder 884)
    - Programs and news clippings, 1980-83 (Box 37, Folder 885)
    - Programs and news clippings, 1983-84 (Box 37, Folder 886)
  - The Philomel Club: booklet, 1927-28 (Box 38, Folder 887)
  - The William Billings Institute of American Music, 1983? (Box 38, Folder 888)
  - Eva Gauthier Society for Living Song: correspondence, minutes, announcement, by-laws, 1959-60 (Box 38, Folder 889)
  - List of piano recitals and other solo performances given by John Duke at Smith College, 1923-66 (Box 38, Folder 890)
  - Programs
    - Performances by students of John Duke, 1935-82 (Box 38, Folder 891)
    - Performances by John Duke or of John Duke compositions, 1931-54 (Box 38, Folder 892-907)
    - Performances by students of John Duke, 1935-82 (Box 38, Folder 891)
    - Performances by John Duke or of John Duke compositions, 1931-54 (Box 38, Folder 892-907)
    - Performances by John Duke or of John Duke compositions, 1955-84 (Box 39, Folder 908-927)
- Series V. SPEAKING AND WRITING, 1920-1984
  This series consists primarily of texts of lectures, lecture-recitals, articles, and book manuscripts. Unless otherwise noted the folders in this section contain text and nothing else. Speaking consists of general addresses arranged by title, class lectures arranged by course title, and lecture-recitals arranged by title. Writing consists of articles and book manuscripts arranged by title plus scrapbooks and miscellaneous notes arranged chronologically.
  - Speaking
    - "The American Song", undated (Box 40, Folder 928)
    - "Art and Intelligence," Cummington School of the Arts: outline, undated (Box 40, Folder 929)
    - "A Comparison of Post-Impressionist Music and Post-Impressionist Painting": notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 930)
    - "A Composer Looks at Contemporary American Song Literature," National Association of Teachers of Singing, n d. (Box 40, Folder 931)
    - Remarks at memorial service for Oliver Larkin, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 932)
    - "What is a Song?" San Antonio, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 933)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 934)
    - Class Lectures
      - Art 34b summer school, "The Arts Today", undated (Box 40)
        - "The Arts and the Intellect. (Box 40, Folder 935-936)
        - "Contemporary Music and Democracy" (Box 40, Folder 937)
        - "The Problem of the Universal in Contemporary Art" (Box 40, Folder 938)
        - "Professionalism in the Arts Today or Art as Big Business" (Box 40, Folder 939)
        - "The Contemporary Composer and His Public" (Box 40, Folder 940)
        - "Is Music Abstract?" (Box 40, Folder 941)
      - University extension course, "The History of Technical Theory in Piano Playing", 1931 (Box 40, Folder 942)
      - Music 313, "The Literature of the Pianoforte": syllabus, undated (Box 40, Folder 943)
    - Lecture-Recitals
      - "Emily Bronte in Poetry and Song," text by John and Dorothy Duke, 1975-76 (Box 40)
        - Introduction (Box 40, Folder 944)
        - Commentary on Emily Bronte (Box 40, Folder 945)
        - Complete script, 1975 May 6 (Box 40, Folder 946)
        - Complete script, later version, undated (Box 40, Folder 947)
        - Commentary on poems, undated (Box 40, Folder 948)
      - Schubert, undated (Box 40, Folder 949)
      - Songs in English, undated (Box 40, Folder 950)
  - Writing
    - "Art and the Glory of God": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 951)
    - "A Kinaesthetic Approach to Piano Technic": typescript, undated (Box 40, Folder 952)
    - "The Legato Principle, 1931 Sep 20 (Box 40, Folder 953)
    - "Louis Moreau Gottschalk, 1968 Mar 4 (Box 40, Folder 954)
    - "Music and the English Language," Motive, 1953 Feb (Box 40, Folder 955)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934; 1968 (Box 40, Folder 956)
    - "The Nature and Significance of Song," National Association of Teachers of Singing Bulletin, 1984 Jan-Feb (Box 40, Folder 957)
    - The Nature of the Pianist's Gift, undated (Box 40)
      - Proposal (Box 40, Folder 958)
      - Introduction, Preface (Box 40, Folder 959)
      - Chapter I, "The Basic Problem Defined" (Box 40, Folder 960)
      - Chapter II, "Physiological Mechanics" (Box 40, Folder 961)
      - Chapter III, "The Quality of Movement (Box 40, Folder 962-963)
      - Chapter IV, "From Theory to, undated (Box 40, Folder 964)
    - "Some Reflections on the Art of Song in English," The American Music Teacher, 1976 Feb-Mar; undated (Box 41, Folder 965)
    - "Technic and Rhythm: An Essay on the Psychological Problems of Piano Playing"
      - Typescript, undated (Box 41, Folder 966)
      - Manuscript, draft 1, undated (Box 41, Folder 967-968)
      - Manuscript, draft 2, undated (Box 41, Folder 969-970)
    - Scrapbook, 1920-26 (Box 41, Folder 971)
    - Scrapbook of reviews and columns written for the Daily Hampshire Gazette, 1925-35 (Box 41, Folder 972)
    - Journal and scrapbook, 1930 (Box 41, Folder 973)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 974)
- Series VI. RECORDINGS, 1939-1984
  This series consists primarily of private recordings of Duke's compositions and performances. It is divided into two sections: Tapes and Discs. The recordings are filed according to the six categories designated by John Duke: Songs, Choral Works, Symphonic Works, Dramatic Works, Solo Pieces and Chamber Music, and Miscellaneous. Recordings which do not include John Duke compositions have been placed with the miscellaneous works. Tapes have been divided into two categories: Reel-to-Reel and Cassette. The items in this series have been listed according to available information.
  - Tapes: Reel-to-Reel
    - Songs, miscellaneous (Box 42)
      - Smith College Music Department (2 tapes), 1983 Jan (Box 42)
      - Pupils of Grace Donovan, n. d. (Box 42)
      - Adrienne Auerswald and Robert Miller, 1974 Sep 22 (Box 42)
      - Adrienne Auerswald and John Duke, 1973 Apr 5 (Box 42)
      - Oscar McCullough, 1965 (Box 42)
      - Richard Rivers and John Duke (Box 42)
      - John Hanks and John Duke, 1963 Nov 5 (Box 42)
      - Jon Humphrey and Calliope Shenas, 1973 Apr 5 (Box 42)
      - Carol Bogard and John Duke (2 tapes) (Box 42)
      - Master class at American University, 1978 Nov 6 (Box 42)